AUDREY THOMASSON

UI/UX DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Contact



615.200.8357



audreyux dev@gmail.com



github.com/audreythomasson



linkedin.com/in/audrey-thomasson

ABOUT

A designer with management experience currently adding HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, and UI/UX design to my skillset. I am originally from Texas where I earned my degree in Graphic Design at Texas State University just outside of Austin. Since moving to Nashville in 2009, I have had the opportunity to explore the city while photographing real estate. I love the artistic side of real estate photography but I recently I found myself researching software development. I've always been fascinated with the tech industry and I am thrilled to get the opportunity to learn programming skills at a place like Nashville Software School. I can't wait to join the working tech community!

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER (APPRENTICESHIP)

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL 2020 - CURRENT

- Intensive full-time six-month bootcamp focusing on front-end development, UI/UX fundamentals, problem-solving and working in a remote team environment
- · Built single page apps individually and by teams with full CRUD functionality
- Focus on user experience with intentional design around speed, efficiency, and functionality
- · Utilize source code version control with Git/GitHub
- · Main technologies covered: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, JSON, Node.js, Git, and GitHub

FRONT-END CAPSTONE PROJECT: TRAVELSHOTS

Time to complete: 2 Weeks - October 2020

Website that lets traveling photographers save and organize photo shoot ideas

- Built to demonstrate my knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React
- · Incorporates Semantic UI external component library
- · Cloudinary API is used to store and manage images uploaded by the user
- All data including the created Cloudinary image link is stored in a JSON server
- · Saved ideas for the shot list have full CRUD (Create, Read, Update, and Delete)

https://github.com/AudreyThomasson/capstone-react-travel-shots

REAL ESTATE PHOTOGRAPHER & MARKETING MANAGER

FREELANCE- NASHVILLE, TN: 2010 - 2020

- Photograph and film real estate for MLS listings primarily with a large Keller Williams group as well as independent agents and property owners
- · Documented property specs and researched property information
- · Listed properties on MLS and wrote marketing information and captions
- · Launched marketing materials for listings on various websites

Tools & Technology

HTML5

CSS3

Javascript

ReactJS

Visual Studio Code

NPM

JSON Server

Figma

Sass

FireBase

Bootstrap

Semantic UI

Slack

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Git and GitHub version control

Command line work flow

Springer-Miller Host & SpaSoft

EZ Labor Payroll

MindBody Online Scheduling Software

Skills

User Testing

UX Research

User Personas

Wireframes

Usability Testing

Journey Mapping

Interactive Prototypes / Mockups

Remote Teamwork

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

ASSISTANT MARKETING MANAGER

JOYMOVES PILATES STUDIO- AUSTIN, TX: 2007 - 2010

- · Design marketing materials including online content, direct mail pieces, business cards, ads
- · Write and edit copy for marketing materials
- · Photography Pilates Studio and pilates poses for use in print and online
- · Log transactions and attendance in MindBody Online Scheduling Software, insure accuracy of all billing procedures
- · Interview potential job candidates and train new hires
- · Continue design services on freelance basis after move to Nashville

SPA SUPERVISOR

LAKE AUSTIN SPA RESORT- AUSTIN, TX: 2004 - 2007

- Responsible for daily operation of 25,000 sq ft luxury spa facility with a staff of over 130
- · Provide customer service to a high-end clientele while developing and executing all policies and standards of customer service to maintain five star service reputation
- · Forecast business levels to ensure that the spa is staffed appropriately including daily management of over 50 therapists' schedules to provide treatments for over 100 daily quests
- · Hire and train coordinators and locker room attendants
- Monitor and insure accuracy of all billing procedures for spa and resort guests
- Guest & employee problem resolution
- Order products and maintain inventory including coordination of product (kits) for treatments

DESIGNER / PRODUCTION MANAGER

UNITED PARENTING PUBLICATIONS- DALLAS, TX: 2001 - 2003

- · Designed classified ads and page layouts for 22 unique monthly parenting magazines
- · Organized workflow for production department and tracked status of all ads in production
- · Coordinated ad creation and changes with sales staff in home office as well as other states
- · Insured accuracy of all ads, layouts, and files transmitted to printing facility
- · Adhered to strict printing schedule while meeting all deadlines
- Designed marketing promotions for the sales staff to increase revenue

Education

UI/UX Design & Front-End Development

Nashville Software School Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS, Cum Laude Communication / Graphic Design

Texas State University

